# HENRY UMANSKY

6 Colton Ct  $\diamond$  Hamilton, NJ 08619 humansky@gmail.com  $\diamond$  (267) 408-7622

#### **OVERVIEW**

Information Technology professional capable of building and managing complex projects from concept to completion. Team player with an excellent eye for detail, noticing and addressing potential obstacles and problems on the way. Highly motivated, responsible and dedicated to work. Always trying to save time and money for the company by looking at the large picture from early phases of every project. Ready to share knowledge and learn. Experienced Project Leader managing several projects in programming spanning over 10 years. Looking for a similiarly motivated company that shares my love and passion for new and emerging technology.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Princeton University**

Manager, Web Programming

2006-present Princeton, NJ

My primary responsibilities include web development, design, and support for OITs Web Development Services group, working in collaboration with other groups within OIT and the rest of the University. I am responsible for all aspects of Web site development, including application coding, testing and deployment, maintenance, and system administration using a combination of coding and productivity tools. In addition, I provide training and support to members of the University who use the Roxen Content Management System. Other major responsibilities include:

- · Leading development and technical support efforts.
- · Managing performance of team members.
- · Developing web applications.
- · Analyzing requirements, defining tasks, and accurately scoping effort.
- · Aligning development efforts with service strategy and project goals.
- · Ensuring development work is delivered on time and within scope.
- · Collaborating with the groups design team.
- · Partnering with other groups in OIT to ensure technical needs of service are met.
- · Partnering with other groups in OIT to ensure that the web infrastructure is meeting the groups needs.
- · Providing end-user technical support online, via phone and in-person.
- · Supporting organizational project management methods and technologies.
- · Maintaining positive relationships with all constituents and stakeholders.

## Misha of Siberia Inc

2004-2006

 $Independent\ Consultant$ 

Philadelphia, PA

My primary responsibilities consisted of:

- · Application design and system administrator.
- · Setup and maintenance of several Linux servers, including web, email, VPN, and DNS server.
- $\cdot$  Designed and implemented an invoice, inventory tracking, A/R, A/P, receipt software using VB.NET and Microsoft SQL Server.
- · Implemented a stand-alone Virtual PBX telecommunication system using open-source Asterisk software and Cisco VoIP hardware.

2001-2004 Pittsburgh, PA

My primary responsibilities consisted of: web-based software development, systems administration, and provision of technical support to the University community. In addition to the able responsibilities I also assisted in providing outstanding customer service to the University community. I helped to support a diverse customer base on a large number of platforms including Solaris, Linux, Mac OS, and Windows. I also assisted in supporting customers on Network and Telecommunications related issues. I was also responsible for the deployment of several Linux-based web/database servers for use by the University Technology Help Desk. These servers provide a number of web based applications that allow Help Desk analysts to perform their jobs more efficiently and access information that is vital to their providing quality customer service. These applications include:

- · A web based tool allowing analysts to quickly and easily respond to a large volume of support requests via email.
- · An authorization system to allow/deny access to certain areas of the internal Help Desk website for specific users and groups. I also developed a web based front-end for this security system to allow administrators to create users and groups and assign rights to those users/groups.
- · A set of scripts to streamline reporting on Help Desk call/ticket statistics. These scripts are responsible for extracting data from a variety of sources, formatting that data, and importing that data into a large centralized database.

#### TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

PHP, XML/XSL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C, C++, Java, Perl Computer Languages

Drupal, Zend, Symfony, JQuery Web Frameworks

**Databases** MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, NoSQL (MongoDB) Tools Git, Capistrano, Jenkins, Apache, Nginx, Varnish

### **EDUCATION**

# University of Pittsburgh

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

June 2004

#### AWARDS & CERTIFICATES

Zend PHP 5.3 Certified Engineer September 2012

Princeton University Management Development Certificate November 2010

August 2010 ITIL v3 Foundation Certificate

Office of Information Technology Service Award February 2008 September 2007 Office of Information Technology Service Award

June 2007 Princeton University Information Technology Achievement Award

#### REFERENCES

Available upon request